<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Soukthavy Sopha (U-Boot)</title><link>http://souktha.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://souktha.github.io/categories/cat_u-boot.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 02:50:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>https://getnikola.com/</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Adding PCIe support and bring up the boot splash screen to DM814x U-Boot</title><link>http://souktha.github.io/software/dm814x_pcie/</link><dc:creator>Soukthavy</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is desirable to have some visual feedback to user during system boot up process especially if the system takes more
than few seconds to boot. For the Linux based set-top box that boot to the main GUI menu may take considerable
amount of time depending on the number of processes it needs to start. Some system may need to program the FPGA bitmask,
bring up the networking processes or bring up some externally connected devices. These steps add up to the total system boot up
time. For system with video support, it is a good practice to have video up as soon as possible so that the user
would know that the system is working and it is in the process of booting up the system. This is commonly known as
putting the boot splash screen during boot process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://souktha.github.io/software/dm814x_pcie/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (10 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>software</category><guid>http://souktha.github.io/software/dm814x_pcie/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 22:18:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Adding SATA HD boot support to DM814x U-Boot</title><link>http://souktha.github.io/software/dm814x_sata/</link><dc:creator>Soukthavy</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;TI DM814x/AM287x evaluation platform (TI8148 EVM) can boot from various connected devices depending on the setting
of the BTMode[4-0] pins as described in chapter 4.5.2.1 of its respective technical reference manual [&lt;a class="reference internal" href="http://souktha.github.io/software/dm814x_sata/#id1"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;]. Typically
the EVM boot its first stage of u-boot as the minimum boot loaders. TI calls it &lt;em&gt;min-nand&lt;/em&gt; boot loader
configuration. This minimum boot then bootstraps a secondary boot phase which is a
a full featured u-boot for this platform.
The EV platform has SATA H/W support where I will bring up the SATA HDD in the second phase of booting so that I can load the
Linux kernel image from HDD instead of loading it from NAND device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://souktha.github.io/software/dm814x_sata/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (5 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>software</category><guid>http://souktha.github.io/software/dm814x_sata/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 20:13:36 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>